ImageNet is a database of over 10 million hand labeled images,
ImageNet 是一个拥有超过 1 千万张手动标记图片的数据库
drawn from 1000 different image categories.
这些图片来自 1000 个不同的图片类别
Since 2010, the ImageNet project has held
自 2010 年起 ImageNet 项目每年都会举办
the ImageNet large scale visual recognition competition,
大规模视觉识别比赛
an annual competition where teams try to build
在这场年度比赛中 各个团队会尝试构建
the best CNN for object recognition and classification.
最佳对象识别和分类 CNN
The first breakthrough was in 2012.
在 2012 年第一次出现突破
The network called AlexNet,
该网络叫做 AlexNet
was developed by a team at the University of Toronto.
由多伦多大学的一个团队开发而成
Using the best GPUs available in 2012,
AlexNet 团队使用在 2012 年最强大的 GPU
the AlexNet team trained the network in about a week.
在一周内训练完该网络
AlexNet pioneered the use of
AlexNet 在使用 ReLU 激活函数和 dropout
the ReLU activation function and dropout as a technique for avoiding overfitting.
来避免过拟合这一方面走在了前沿
In 2014, two different groups nearly tied in the image net competition.
在 2014 年 有两个小组在这一图片网络竞赛中几乎持平
One of those networks was called VGG Net,
其中一个网络叫做 VGG Net
often referred to as just VGG.
经常简称为 VGG
And it came from the visual geometry group at Oxford University.
由牛津大学的视觉几何组开发而成
VGG has two versions termed VGG 16 and VGG 19,
VGG 具有两个版本：VGG 16 和 VGG 19
with 16 and 19 total layers, respectively.
分别一共有 16 个层级和 19 个层级
Both versions have a simple and elegant architecture,
两个版本的结构都很简单美观
which is just a long sequence of three by three convolutions,
是一个很长的 3x3 卷积序列
broken up by two by two pulling layers and finished with three fully connected layers.
并穿插着 2x2 的池化层 最后是三个完全连接层
VGG pioneered the exclusive use of small three by
VGG 以独特方式使用很小的 3x3 卷积窗口
three convolution windows to contrast AlexNet's much larger 11 by 11 windows.
与 AlexNet 的大型 11x11 窗口形成鲜明对比
In 2015, the ImageNet winner was a network from Microsoft Research called ResNet,
在 2015 年 ImageNet 获胜者是微软研究部门的一个网络 叫做 ResNet
ResNet is kind of like VGG,
ResNet 和 VGG 很相似
and not the same structure is repeated again and again for layer after layer.
并非同一结构不断重复 一层又一层
Also like VGG, ResNet has different versions that vary in their number of layers.
此外 和 VGG 很像的是 ResNet 具有不同的版本 区别在于层级的数量
The largest having a groundbreaking 152 layers.
最大的网络具有破纪录的 152 个层级
Previous researchers tried to make their CNNs this deep,
之前研究人员也尝试过构建这么深的 CNN
but they ran into a problem where as they were adding layers,
但是他们遇到了问题 当他们不断添加层级时
performance increased up to a point after which performance quickly declined.
效果增强到一定的程度之后就快速下降了
This is partially due to what's known as the vanishing gradient problem,
一部分原因是梯度消失问题
which arises when we go to train the network through back propagation.
当我们通过反向传播训练网络时就会出现该问题
The main idea, is that the gradient signal has to be pushed through the entire network.
主要原理是梯度信号需要传递到整个网络中
The deeper the network becomes,
网络越深
the more likely that the signal gets weakened before it gets where it needs to go.
很有可能信号在抵达目的地之前就削弱了
The ResNet team added connections to
ResNet 团队在他们的深度 CNN 中
their very deep CNN that
添加了跳过层级的连接
skipped layers so the gradient signal has a shorter route to travel.
因此梯度信号的传播路径更短
ResNet achieved superhuman performance in classifying images in the ImageNet database.
ResNet 在 ImageNet 数据库的图片分类方面取得了惊人的效果
In Keras, it's a simple task to import ResNet 50.
在 Keras 中 导入 ResNet 50 很简单
Both VGG 16 and VGG 19 are also easily
除了其他两个结构“Inception”和“Exception”之外
accessed through Keras in addition to two other architectures,
VGG 16 和 VGG 19 也可以轻松地
named inception and exception.
通过 Keras 进行访问
We'll show you how to do this in the next video.
我们将在下个视频中介绍如何操作